Previously, on Stargate SG-1...
스타게이트 SG-1은...
끝났네, 잭
It's over, Jack.
No extensions, no reversals,...
기간 연장 같은 것도 없어
..no new hearings.
스타게이트는 사장이야.말 그대로 사장..
The Stargate will be buried,
literally and figuratively.
그 좌표로 게이트를 열어 보면 됩니다
We should attempt to open the gate.
대령님, 돌아오는 즉시 군법회의에 회부될 거예요
We'd be court- martialled
the second we got back.
돌아온다면
If we got back.
We're on an attack ship headed to Earth.
이건 지구로 가는 공격함이에요
위대한 용사 클로렐이다!
The mighty warrior, Klorel.
- I'm gonna grab Skaara.
- Are you sure?
-스카라를 잡을 거야
-진심이세요?
It would be like trying to take Apophis.
아포피스를 잡는 거나 마찬가지예요
죽기 전에 마지막으로 고향을 봐라
You will get to see your home
one last time...
너랑 네 행성의 모두가 사라질 거다
..before you and everyone
on your planet are destroyed.
스카라!
Skaara!
And now, the conclusion.
그들의 최후는...
- Captain Carter?
- Sir?
-카터 대위
-네?
타격을 입힐 만큼C-4 폭탄을 설치했나?
Is there enough C4 around this ship
to make a dent?
The charges should generate
secondary explosions.
제2폭발을 유도할 만한 곳에 설치했습니다
So...yes, sir. Should make a helluva dent.
타격은 확실히 입힐 수 있습니다
고맙네, 대위
Thank you.
-시간이 좀 더 있다면...
-안 돼!
- Given enough time, I may figure out...
- Negative!
적이 곧 저 문을 열고 올 거야...
Their reinforcements
may come any second.
Stand by to detonate your charges
on my order.
명령하면 바로 폭파시키도록 하게
알겠습니다
Yes, sir.
Wait...
잠시만요
대니얼! 지금 못 막으면 영원히 못 막아
Daniel, if we don't stop them now,
we may never stop them.
네, 알아요.
Yeah, I know that.
폭발력을 극대화시켜야죠
Let's just make
as big a dent as possible. OK?
Ready and awaiting your order, sir.
준비됐습니다, 대령님
OK.
좋았어
Well, I suppose now is the time
for me to say something profound.
마지막으로 한마디 할 때인 것 같군...
Nothing comes to mind. Let's do it.
딱히 할말도 없으니 그만 시작하지
O'Neill,...
오닐...아포피스의 함선입니다
..Apophis's ship approaches.
We heard him say he'd rejoin Klorel
once they came out of the shadows.
게이트 실에서 들었는데 클로렐과 합친다고 했어요
Teal'c,...
틸크, 우리가 여길 폭파하면 저들도 포기할까?
..if we can knock out this ship,
will it stop them?
It will not.
아뇨, 아포피스의 함선은 보호막이 있습니다
고공에서 폭격할 겁니다
Apophis's vessel has defence shields.
He can still destroy your cities.
폭탄을 자동 타이머로 작동시켜놨다고 해 줘
Tell me those C4 charges
are on an automatic timer.
그렇게 했습니다
They are.
-좋았어, 얼마 후지?
-24시간입니다
- Good. How long do we have?
- 24 hours.
스물 네 시간?
24 hours?
그땐 우리가 몇 광년 떨어져 있는 줄 알았어요
At the time, sir,
I thought we were still light years away.
-
- Just a minute!
잠깐 기다리게!
Teal'c, work with me, buddy.
Is there any other way outta here?
틸크... 생각해 봐 다른 출구가 있나?
None.
없습니다
Cover up.
숨어...
This is turning out to be a bad day.
오늘 운수가 안 좋군
Agh!
≪ S A T R G A T E ≫
주연/리처드 딘 앤더슨
스타게이트SG-1
마이클 솅크스
아만다 태핑
크리스토퍼 저지
돈 S 데이비스
오닐
O'Neill?
틸크
Teal'c...
소제목/뱀굴 (The Serpent's Lair)
Aah...
틸크, 아무것도 안 보여
Teal'c,...
..I can't see.
저도 안 보입니다.곧 괜찮아질 겁니다
I am blinded as well. It will pass.
What the hell was that?
방금 그건 뭐였지?
가우울드 '쇼크 탄'입니다
고통스럽지만 잠시뿐이죠
A Goa'uld shock grenade.
Though extremely painful,
its effects are temporary.
That's good to hear.
다행이군
이런! 젠장!
Ow!
God! Ow!
대령님?
Colonel?
Sorry, sir. It's just so dark.
죄송합니다.너무 어두워서요
Oh...Carter!
카터!괜찮아... 자세가 됐군
It's all right. I like your attitude.
어두운 게 아니고,눈이 먼 거예요
It isn't dark. We're blind.
And we failed.
우린 실패했어요
괜찮네, 대니얼 더 심한 적도 있었잖아
All right, take it easy, Daniel.
We've been in worse situations than this.
제 기억엔 없는데요
Not to my knowledge.
Thanks, Teal'c.
고맙군, 틸크
Right now they're preparing
to wipe out the major cities of Earth.
저들이 지구를 폭격한다 해도 우린 아무 수도 쓸 수 없어요
They'll do it from orbit, out of reach.
대니얼
Daniel...
잭, 난 이미 겪은 상황이에요 벌써 본 거라구요
Jack, I've been through this once before.
I've seen this before.
대니얼! 마음 좀 가라앉혀
Daniel, will you relax?
전에도 우린 살아 남았잖아
오늘... 재수가 없을 뿐이야
You've been through it before
and you survived.
We're...just having a bad day.
대령님, 이제 뭐가 좀 보입니다
Colonel, I think
I'm starting to see something.
내 시야도 돌아옵니다
- My sight returns as well.
- That's what I wanna hear.
반가운 소리군
카터 누가 다가오면...손을 물게나
Carter,...
..if someone comes in here, you...
..bite'em in the hand.
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다
Tal kree, shak!
죄송합니다, 다신 클로렐을 실망시키지 않겠습니다
Forgive me, master.
I will not fail Klorel again.
이제 기회가 없다
No.
You will not.
도대체 여기서 뭐 하는 거지?
What the hell are you doing here?
Reporting for duty, sir.
I'm to coordinate with the Pentagon.
신고합니다, 펜타곤 연락장교로 임명받았습니다
-누구 명령이지?
-합참의장입니다
- By whose order?
- At the request of Senator Kinsey.
킨지 의원님이 연락했을 텐데요...
He did try to contact you.
경계령이 안 내려진 이유나 말해 보게
지금 준비를 안 하면 꼼짝없이 당한단 말일세
Why aren't our forces on full alert?
펜타곤에선 가우울드가 방심하게 만들려는 것입니다
If we don't move now
they'll be caught on the ground.
The Pentagon don't want to alert
the Goa'uld we know they're there.
Let me guess whose bright idea that was.
누가 그런 멋진 생각을 했는지 맞춰볼까?
General Hammond, may I speak freely?
장군님, 제 생각을 말씀드리죠 원인이야 알 수 없겠지만
I seem to have lost your respect, sir,
for whatever reason,...
가우울드가 전쟁을 일으키진 않았을 겁니다
..but we wouldn't be in this situation,
that is,...
..at the brink of war with the Goa'uld,...
제 의견을 받아들이고 게이트를 봉쇄했다면 말이죠
..if you had heeded my advice
and buried the Stargate.
'거봐, 내가 말했잖아' 이건가?
Was that "I told you so",
Colonel Samuels?
I'm not here to point fingers, sir.
그런 말을 하러 온 게 아닙니다, 장군님
I'm here to help coordinate our
pre- emptive strike against the Goa'uld.
전 선제공격을 돕기 위해 왔습니다
대통령 승인이 있어야겠지만 합참에서 브리핑 중입니다
That's if the President approves.
He's being briefed now.
뭘로 공격할 생각이지?
- With what do you intend to strike?
- A new weapon, sir.
51구역에서 메이본 대령과 함께 개발한 신무기입니다
I've helped to oversee
its development at area 51.
Two prototypes are being prepared
for launch at Vandenberg Air Force base.
2개의 시제품이 반덴버그 기지에서 대기중입니다
역사는 정체불명의 화염이었다고 기록하겠죠
If all goes well,
history should mark this day...
..by two brilliant and unexplained flashes
that occur in the night sky.
아마겟돈에 다가선 줄도 모르구요
The world should never know
how close we came to Armageddon.
- Kel Klorel?
- Your son was struck down by humans.
아드님께서 함선에 있던 지구인에게 당하셨습니다
-석관엔 바로 넣었나?
-그렇습니다
He is in his sarcophagus?
Yes, my lord, but his wounds were great.
하지만 상처가 심해서 시간이 좀 걸릴 것 같습니다
It will take time to revive him.
-지구인들은?
-클로렐님이 깨신 후에
- What of the humans?
- I thought to wait until Klorel...
안 된다! 즉시 처형해라
No!
Execute them now!
책임지고 하겠습니다
I will see to it myself.
We hold our position.
지정된 위치입니다 지구인들은 아직 반응이 없습니다
The humans of this world
still send no challenge.
Yet they find their way to my son.
내 아들에게 찾아왔군
클로렐이 깨어나면 공격을 개시하겠다
We will attack their world
when Klorel has risen again.
수백 배로 갚아 주지
They will pay a hundredfold
for their insolence.
Kel sha, Apophis.
가우울드가 머뭇거려서 시간을 벌었습니다
궤도 진입시 요격합니다
The Goa'uld's unexplained delay
is buying us time to prepare.
We'll strike as soon as they enter orbit.
신무기가 뭐가 그리 대단하지?
What makes this weapon so special?
An otherwise ordinary
Mk 12- A warhead,...
사뮤엘 다른 것은 같습니다만
'마하 12A'의 탄두는 나콰다로 채워졌죠
..has been enriched
by the alien material naqahdah.
스타게이트 재료인가?
- The Stargate element?
- Yes, sir.
그렇습니다.아시겠지만 얼마 전 SG5가
조그만 광산을 발견했죠
A small amount of the raw ore
was found by SG- 5 and brought back.
각각의 탄두는 천 메가톤 급입니다
The warheads should now yield
in excess of 1, 000 megatons...each.
We call them our Goa'uld busters.
'가우울드 킬러'라 부르죠
궤도 진입 후 역 추진시 발사할 예정입니다
나콰다를 실은 탄두엔..스텔스 기술이 적용됐습니다
Our plan is to launch two rockets
simultaneously into retrograde orbit.
Now, the naqahdah- enriched warheads...
..are made of the same material
as our Stealth aircraft,...
그래서... 발견되지 않고 접근할 수 있죠
..and should go undetected by their radar.
가우울드도 레이더를 쓴다면 말이겠지...
Assuming the Goa'uld
have anything remotely like radar.
최선의 선택입니다 대통령도 동의하시고
카운트다운을 지시하셨죠 현재 발사 3시간 전입니다
It's our best shot, sir.
And I'm sure the President agrees
or he wouldn't have initiated countdown.
Currently,
we stand at T minus three hours.
사정 거리 내에 들어오면 2분으로 조정됩니다
We'll hold at two minutes
while the Goa'uld come within range.
잘될 겁니다, 장군님
가우울드의 허를 찌르는 거죠
It's going to work, sir.
The Goa'uld should be taken off guard.
자네가 틀렸다면 전세계 모든 나라가 당하는 거고
If you're wrong, every country on Earth
will be caught off guard.
-할 수만 있다면 경계령을...
-죄송합니만 장군님
If it were up to me,
I'd recommend warning...
With respect, sir, it's not up to you.
장군님 권한밖입니다
그나마 이제 내 손이 뿌옇게 안 보여 다행이군
Well, on the bright side,
my hand isn't blurry any more.
틸크...
Teal'c?
Bra'tac?
브라탁?
Oh, God!
Fools! Hashak!
바보들! 죽으려고 작정했군!
이게 자네들을 살릴 수 있는 유일한 길일세
You doom yourselves.
It is all I can do to keep you alive!
Do you know all I have done
to regain the trust of Apophis...
이번 공격에 나서기 위해 내가 어떤 짓을 한 줄 아나?
..and join this campaign? Hmm?
Hmm?
Tek matte, Bra'tac.
Hello again, old friend.
다시 만나 반갑군, 친구 자네 아들은 건강하네
Your son grows strong.
훌륭한 전사가 될 거야.이곳에 오는 게 아녔어!
One day, he will be a great warrior.
But you should not have come.
I stand by my friends.
내 동료들과 함께할 겁니다
이들 거짓 신들을 물리칠 유일한 희망입니다
This world may be our only hope
in one day overcoming the false gods.
맞아, 지금은 불쌍해 죽겠지만...
Yes.
As pathetic as that may seem
at the moment,...
..I agree.
나도 동의해
You do?
-그래요?
-당신들이 방해만 안 했어도 구할 수 있었을 텐데!
I may even have been able
to save this world had you not interfered.
이봐요!우리가 여길 왜 왔는데요?
Hey!
What do you think
we've been trying to do?
-그곳은 우리 세계라구요!
-그만하게!
It is our world you're talking about.
Enough, human!
여기서 말할 일이 아냐!
아포피스가 자네들을 처형하라고 명령했어
This is not the place to talk.
I have been ordered by Apophis himself
to execute you.
그 명령을 어기기로 했네
An order I intend to disregard.
Come!
이리 오게!
- Kill the gate, Corporal!
- Yes, sir!
아직 움직임이 없나?
They still haven't moved?
지난 18시간 동안 꼼짝 않고 있습니다
No, sir. Not for the last 18 hours.
도대체 뭘 기다리는 거지?
What in God's name are they waiting for?
제 전략 분석팀에 의하면 우리 태도를 관찰 중이랍니다
My mission analysis team believes
they're waiting to see what we do.
러시아나 중국은 아직 그들을 감지하지 못한 것 같습니다
Amazingly, the Russians and Chinese
haven't detected the Goa'uld presence.
물론 찾지 않아서겠지만...
Of course, they're not looking.
So, from space,...
..we should appear to be
a vulnerable and unsuspecting world.
따라서 우주에서 보기에 우린 약하고 선량해 보이겠죠
자네가 원하는 건가, 사뮤엘?
Got'em just where you want'em?
There may be another reason
why they haven't attacked.
장군님... 다른 이유가 있을지도 모릅니다
컴퓨터 확대 결과...
에너지 유출이 그들의 함교로 추정되는 곳에서 있었습니다
We have the computer enhancement.
There was an energy burst, coming
from the bridge of one of the ships,...
17시 50분 경입니다 멈추기 직전이죠
..recorded at 1750 hours.
Just before they stopped.
That's it?
그래서?
For all we know, that flash could be
part of their ship's normal function.
어쩌면 함선의 정상적인 현상인지도 모르잖나
Except that the burst came from
within the ship. It was powerful.
하지만 선 내에서 발생했고 꽤 강력했습니다
폭발이었나? 사고?
Maybe an explosion? An accident?
Or sabotage.
-폭파시켰거나!
-SG1일까요?
SG-1.
아니라고 봅니다
우주선으로는 게이트 이동이 불가능합니다
I hardly think so.
For one thing,
it's impossible to gate to a ship.
Forgive me, sir.
I know how important SG-1 is to you,...
SG1을 아끼는 마음은 알지만 부질없는 생각입니다
..but this is wishful thinking.
자네도 마찬가지야, 우린 우리 계획을 밀고 나갈 걸세
So's your plan. That hasn't stopped us
going ahead with it.
General Hammond, the first group
on the Alpha list has just arrived.
-하몬드 장군님, 알파 지역에 보낼 인원이 도착했습니다
-고맙네
Thank you.
자네 무기일세.필요할 거야
Here are your weapons.
You will need them.
브라탁, 우리 세계를 구한다고 했죠? 어떻게요?
Um, Bra'tac, you mentioned
something about...saving the world?
- Care to elaborate on that?
- By assaulting Klorel,...
클로렐을 공격해서 이젠 불가능해
- ..you have made that impossible.
- Why?
왜죠?
가우울드 파라오에겐 적보다도 아들이 위험하지
A pharaoh's power
is more often challenged by their sons...
..than by their enemies.
전쟁이 터지면 아포피스를 공격하려 했어
Once we had joined battle
with your world,...
..I was prepared to lead my wing
against Apophis, in Klorel's name.
클로렐을 앞세워서
아포피스는 클로렐이 배신한 줄 알고 반격하구요
대담한 계획입니다
Apophis would assume your attack
was ordered by Klorel and reciprocate.
A daring plan.
그들을 이간질해야 하는데 이제 공동의 적이 생겼으니
I had hoped to drive
a stake of mistrust between them.
Now they will bond
against their common enemy.
공동의 적이요? 클로렐은 죽었잖아요
What bond?
- Klorel's dead.
- He will rise again.
다시 일어날걸세
The sarcophagus.
그 석관...
잠깐만요...다시 깨어나게 넣었다는 건가요?
Wait a minute. You put him
in that thing to bring him back?
깨어날 때까진 공격하지 않을 걸세
I knew it would delay their attack
until he arose.
그 사이에 당신네 함선이 준비되면 우리도...
Perhaps when the warships
of your world attack, we...
저... 우리 함선이요?
Uh, excuse me, did you say
the ships of our world?
물론 선대 정돈 있겠지?
You have such vessels?
Well,...we have a number of...of...
몇 개가 있죠...
-셔틀이라고
-셔틀...
Shuttles.
그 셔틀이란 거...쓸 만한가?
These...shuttles,...
..they are a formidable craft?
Oh, yeah.
그럼요...그래요...
Yeah.
Bad day.
큰일났군
Ladies and gentlemen,
as you have all been made aware,...
제군 여러분도 이미 알다시피...
Chevron four encoded.
제4문자 해독
이 나라, 전 세계가 위험에 빠졌다
..this nation,...
..the entire world, faces a deadly threat.
제5문자 해독!
Chevron five encoded.
여러분은 인류 보존을 위해 이번 임무에 자원했다
여러분이 선택된 이유는 여러분이 최고이기 때문이다
With this knowledge,
you have all volunteered for a mission...
..intended to preserve humankind.
You've been chosen because
you represent the best we have...
..in all fields of expertise.
제6문자 해독!
Chevron six encoded.
What you have not yet been told,
for reasons of security,...
어디로 어떻게 가는지는 설명해 줄 수 없지만
..is where you're going
or how you're going to get there.
Chevron seven locked.
제7문자 고정!
저길 통과해야 한다 일단 게이트를 통과하면
우주 반대편일 것이다
You're going to step through that.
Once through the Stargate,...
..you will find yourself
on the opposite side of this galaxy.
우리가 알파 구역이라 부르는 곳이지
A place we call Alpha site.
이곳이 함락당한다면 그곳에 뼈를 묻어라
새로운 식민지이다
If we do not prevail,...
..you, and those that follow,...
..will call it...home.
A new colony.
은총이 있길
Godspeed.
Kel mak tak, Tauri!
저 세계를 불바다로 만들겠어!
Let us burn their world to ashes.
They're moving.
움직입니다!
Restart the countdown.
카운트다운 재시작! 20분부터 개시
궤도 진입 즉시 발사할 수 있도록!
Hold at T minus 20 seconds.
We'll launch the weapons
the moment they settle into orbit.
속력을 높였습니다 클로렐이 깨어났군요
We accelerate. Klorel has risen.
전쟁이 시작됐군 하는 데까진 해 봐야지
Then the campaign has begun.
Once we launch,
we will do what damage we can.
How many in your wing?
당신 편대는 몇 명이죠?
셋이오
Three.
Three?
셋?
Teal'c makes four.
-틸크까지 넷이군
-아, 넷이군요
Oh, well, four.
'찰티'일 때부터 이들을 가르쳤소
내게 목숨을 맡겼지 쉬운 일은 아니었어
I have trained these warriors
since they were Chal'tii.
They have sworn their lives to me.
It is no simple thing to ask.
And we appreciate it.
성의는 고맙지만 소형 전투기 네 대로 공격이 가능한가요?
셔틀이 있다 해도...
But what are the odds of
taking out a ship like this...
..with four gliders and...maybe a shuttle?
가우울드 함대는 두꺼운 장갑에
보호막까지 갖고 있죠.거의 불가능합니다
A Goa'uld attack vessel is armed,...
..shielded, and capable of launching
a legion of gliders against us.
I would say...slim.
비관주의자라고 해도 좋으니 새 계획을 짜자구
OK. Call me a pessimist,
but it's time for a new plan.
당신 세계를 위해 우리 목숨을 걸었소
더 이상 뭘 바라오?
We offer to lay down our lives
for your world, human.
You cannot ask more.
그게 아니에요
우리 세계를 위한 거니까 우리 목숨부터 걸자는 거죠
No. But I think a better idea
is to get the other guys...
..to lay down their lives
for their world first.
C-4가 폭파되는 시간은?
How long before the C4 goes?
41분 남았습니다
41 minutes, sir.
운이 좋다면 한시간 내에 여긴 폭파될 겁니다
OK, with any luck at all,
this ship is gonna blow within the hour.
It might be a good idea for us
to get to the other one.
그 전에 다른 곳으로 가죠 갈 수 있나요?
Can you do that?
좋았어, 미국 상공에 있어!공격 목표에 입력시키게
대통령께 준비됐다고 보고하게
They're in a geosynchronous orbit
over the United States.
Lock in that attack profile,...
..and advise the President
we are go for launch.
Vandenberg reports a good launch.
반덴버그 발사는 성공입니다
좋았어! 죄송합니다, 장군님...
SG1은 안에 없었을 겁니다
Yes!
I'm sorry, sir. For what it's worth,...
..I seriously doubt SG-1
is aboard those alien ships.
4분 후 목표에 도달합니다
Weapons should reach their targets in...
..four minutes.
Let's keep moving these people
through to the Alpha site.
그 동안 이 사람들을 알파 지역으로 이송하게
Group nine, prepare to disembark.
9번째 그룹, 출발 준비!
더 보내기 전에 요격 결과부터 보시죠
Let's wait and see the result of our strike,
before moving more people through.
-과연 그럴까?
-대피할 필요도 없을 겁니다
- I don't think so.
- Evacuation may be unnecessary.
하느님께 빌어 보자구
From your mouth to God's ears, Colonel.
Have you more of this 4- C?
-4C라는 거 더 있나?
-C-4라는 거예요
It's called C4.
- And no. We used it to take out this ship.
- You guys must have something left.
이곳에 장착하느라 다 써버렸어요
그쪽은 뭐 없어요?
We shall have to cross that bridge
when we come to it.
때가 되면 다리를 건너야지
그 표현이 항상 적용되는 건... 아니에요
You know,
that particular...cliche doesn't...
..always work.
The warheads have separated.
탄두 분리 요격 1분 전입니다
One minute to go.
- Any indication of countermeasures?
- They won't know what hit'em.
-반격 기미는 없나?
-뭔 줄도 모를 겁니다
My lord, they launch weapons against us.
-적이 우릴 향해 무기를 발사했습니다
-오라고 해
Let them come.
요격 30초 전!
30 seconds to impact.
Still no countermeasures.
아직 반응이 없습니다
어서 가, 가!
Go, go.
무기가 다가옵니다 방어막을 가동해야 합니다
Their weapons approach, my lord.
You must activate the shield.
Klorel, tal shak!
Tal shak!
Impact in seven,...
요격 7, 6, 5...
..six,...
..five,...
이런, 방금 뭐였죠?
Whoa, what was that?
Something may have
impacted the shields.
뭔가가 보호막을 작동시켰군
Reports say the warheads struck
an energy field just prior to impact.
사령부에 따르면 요격 직전 에너지 막에 걸렸답니다
실패했습니다
- No damage.
- That's impossible!
말도 안 돼!
NASA confirms, sir,
the Goa'uld ships are still up there.
나사에서 확인했습니다 가우울드 함선은 건재합니다
Not bad.
제법이군
펠탁은 2층을 더 올라가야 해, 이쪽이야!
The peltak is two decks above. This way!
Yes, sir.
그렇습니다, 폭발로 위성 통신에 장애가 생겼습니다
일반 대중들에게 알릴 방법이 없습니다
The EMP caused by the explosion has
affected our satellite communications.
It's too late to warn the general public.
It will only cause mass panic.
방위 태세를 갖추는 게 좋을 듯 싶습니다
공군 1호기에 탑승하십시오
Mr President, I recommend we maintain
the highest defence condition.
You should board Air Force One.
알겠습니다
Yes, sir.
클로렐, 시간이 됐다
첫 도시를 태워 버려라!
Klorel, it is time.
You will burn their first city to the ground.
Father,
the host you chose for me is strong.
아버지... 고르신 숙주의 저항이 심합니다
석관에서 좀더 있어야 할 것 같습니다
I fear I may need more time
in the sarcophagus to gain strength.
넌 충분히 강해! 내 아들이야!
You are strong enough! You are my son!
알겠습니다
Yes, Father.
날 실망시키지 마라
Do not disappoint me.
Looks clear.
괜찮아 보이는데
No. There are sentries in every corridor.
아냐, 복도마다 초병이 있어
- Carter, how many grenades?
- Two left.
-카터, 수류탄이 몇 개지?
-두 개 남았습니다
수류탄?
- Grenades?
- A crude explosive device.
잔인한 폭발물이죠
안 돼! 보면...만들어 낼 거야
No! Observe...
..and learn.
Ough!
Urgh!
Hmm!
제법이군요
Not bad.
하몬드 장군님, 알파 12,13 팀이 준비됐답니다
General Hammond, Major Castleman
reports Alpha teams 12 and 13...
- ..are briefed and ready to disembark.
- Send them through.
통과시키게
장군님...
General,...
..maybe we should consider
using the Stargate...
스타게이트를 발사대로 사용하는 건 어떨까요?
..as a strategic weapons platform.
어떻게?
How?
잭슨 박사가 가져온 좌표로 폭탄을 보내는 겁니다
출락이든지...
By sending a bomb to the coordinates
Dr Jackson spoke of. Or to Chulak.
잭슨 박사의 좌표로 대원을 보내려 했지만 실패했네
출락에는 보낼 군사적 이유가 전혀 없네
We already tried to send a team through.
It won't work.
And I can't think of any military reason
to wipe out the people of Chulak.
Well, sir,...
그렇다면..전 이곳에 더 이상 필요가 없을 테니
알파 지역으로 가게 해 주십시오
..since I am no longer
wanted or needed here,...
..I respectfully request permission...
..to join a team headed for the Alpha site...
-제가 가면 적어도...
-불허하네! 최고를 보내는 계획이네
Permission denied.
The idea is to send the best and brightest.
When the time comes,...
때가 되면 여길 사수하는 병력에 합류해야 할걸세
..you'll stand with the men and women of
this command, in defence of this facility.
But, sir...
-하지만 장군님!
-더 이상 듣고 싶지 않네
I ask no more or less of myself.
Dismissed!
이만 물러가게
-계획을 말하죠...
-내가 앞장설 테니 따라오게
- All right, here's what we do...
- I will lead. You will follow.
그러죠...
Right.
You will know when it is time.
시간이 되면 알 걸세
잠깐만요, 저길 혼자 들어간다구요?
You're gonna walk in there alone?
I am Klorel's loyal servant.
난 그의 충성스런 신하일세
Bra'tac.
브라탁!
My lord, Klorel.
클로렐 님...
이리 와서...
네 신의 능력의 증인이 돼라
Come.
Witness the power of your god.
그럴 수 없습니다
I cannot.
왜 나를 거스르지?
- Why do you defy me?
- Because you are not a god.
당신은 신이 아니니까
You are a parasite within a child,...
아이에 들어간 기생충일 뿐야! 널 증오한다
..and I despise you.
Jaffa, kree tai!
자파! '카르 타이'! 난 네 신이다!
내 힘을 느끼게 해 주마!
I am your god!
And you will feel my wrath!
난 자유인으로 죽을 거야!
I...
..die...
..free!
Let's go. Daniel, watch our backs.
가자! 대니얼, 뒤를 엄호해!
Orgh!
Jaffa! Tal shak!
잭!
Jack!
Agh!
대니얼! 젠장!
Daniel...
Dammit!
- I'm dead anyway. Just get outta here.
- I am not leaving you here!
-가망이 없어요, 그냥 가요
-그럴 순 없어, 대니얼!
여기서 나가요!
옆 함선도 폭파할 텐데 무슨 차이가 있어요! 가요!
You're just gonna blow up
with the other ship anyway!
What difference does it make? Go!
가요!
Just go!
I'll stay and watch your back.
뒤를 엄호할게요
대니얼은... 남을 거야
He's...staying behind.
오시오!
Come.
Jaffa!
자파! 클로렐!
Come.
오시오! 와요!
Come!
우릴 쏘면 클로렐을 죽일 거다!
If you fire upon us, I will kill Klorel!
브라탁, 감히 네가 날 배신해?
Bra'tac, how dare you betray me?
I have spent 133 years
worshipping false gods.
133년간 가짜 신을 섬겼지만 이젠 아냐!
No more!
Colonel, the C4 on the other ship
goes in six minutes.
저쪽 함선의 C-4가 6분 후에 폭발합니다
How do we blow this ship?
이건 어떻게 폭파하지?
When we were on Klorel's vessel
I directed it closer to this one.
클로렐의 함선에 있을 때 항로를 이쪽으로 바꿨소
If we disable this shield generator,
both vessels will explode.
이 전함의 보호막 발생기를 망가뜨리면 둘 다 폭발하죠
일석이조입니다
Two birds with but one stone.
이쪽이야!
This way.
You disappoint me, my son.
날 실망시켰구나, 아들아
Father, please...
아버지, 제발...용서해 주세요
..forgive me.
The shield generators are far below.
보호막 발생기는 저기 아래쪽에 있어
한참 밑이지
There, in the very bowels of the ship.
We must climb down several decks,
through the length of the ship.
Then, taking our weapons, we must...
폭파시키려면 아래로 내려 가야해
무기를 가져가서...
수류탄이죠!
Grenades.
이 함선엔 이제 보호막이 없습니다
We are no longer protected
by an energy field.
So, that's it?
이게 다예요?
그렇소
That is it.
대위가 묻는 건 이제 뭘... 해야 하는가야
I think what the Captain is asking
is "what now?"
Now we die.
이제 죽어야지
Well, that's a bad plan.
좋은 계획 같지 않은데...전투기 격납고가 어디죠?
Where are the glider bays from here?
장군님, 함선이 서로 가까이 간답니다
Sir, reports say the ships
are moving closer together.
엔디버 호는 어떤 상태인가?
What's the status of the shuttle Endeavor?
발사대에 있습니다
Standing by.
We've got to find out
what's going on up there.
무슨 일인지 알아 봐야겠군
Carter,...
카터...자네랑 내가 먼저가지
역할을 나누자구 아냐, 그냥 하지...
..you and I will go in first.
We'll take up positions...to...
Never mind.
Observe.
보게나 조심!
Cover!
이게 수류탄이란 거요
오시오!
Now, that was a grenade! Come!
인간!이걸 끼게나
Human, put this on.
Will you please stop calling me human?
꼭 그렇게 '인간'이라고 불러야 돼요?
안 돼!
No!
시간이 다됐다! 출격!
Our time is up. We have got to go.
Punch it.
당겨요
장군님! 전국에서 보고가 들어옵니다
밤하늘에 화염이 보인답니다!
Sir, we've got reports
from all over the country!
A huge fireball in the night sky!
Bra'tac?
브라탁 브라탁! 괜찮아요?
Bra'tac!
You OK?
늙은이치곤 괜찮아
Not bad.
For an old man.
-대령님, 들리세요?
-우린 괜찮아, 대위
Colonel? Come in.
We're OK, Captain.
Same here, sir.
여기도 그렇습니다만...시간이 별로 없습니다
파편에 맞은 것 같아요
But we didn't buy ourselves much time.
Our glider's had it.
I concur.
동감입니다
- We got cooked in the explosion.
- Captain...
-폭발 영향이 커요
-대위...
동력도 부족하고 궤도에 너무 가까워요
곧 지구 대기에서 연소될 것 같습니다
We're low on power
and in a fairly low orbit,...
..so it won't be long before
we burn up in Earth's atmosphere.
대위...고개를 들어 봐
Captain,...
..take a look up.
It's beautiful.
멋지군요
Yes, it is.
맞아, 멋지지
우리가 구했습니다
We saved it, sir.
맞아, 그랬어
Yes, we did.
외계 접근! 외계 접근!
SG-1 신호입니다!
Incoming traveller! Incoming traveller!
It's SG-1's signal, sir.
보호막 열어!
Open the iris.
잭슨 박사!
혹시 SG-1이 저 함선에 타고 있었나?
Dr Jackson!
Was SG-1 aboard one of those ships?
Yes.
맞아요!
Well...Well, how did you get...
자넨 어떻게?
함선에 스타게이트가 있었어요
지구와 가까워서 지구를 출발지로 해서
There was a Stargate
aboard the ship we were on.
Once we were close enough to use Earth
as a point of origin, I dialled P3X- 984.
-P3X984로 갔었죠
-알파 지역이군
그쪽에선 베타 지역이라더군요
The Alpha site?
Yeah. They called it the Beta site
in the alternate reality.
Where's the rest of SG-1?
다른 대원들은 어디 있나?
It'll be a beautiful sunset, sir.
-멋진 노을이 되겠군요
-그거 알아? 재수 없는 날은 아니었어
You know, Captain,...
..this wasn't such a bad day after all.
Not bad at all.
절대 아니에요
우린 잘 죽는 거야, 틸크
We die well, Teal'c.
More than that, old friend.
가장 멋진 죽음이죠.자유인으로 죽는 거니까
We die free.
Or not.
아닐 수도 있어
Uh, Houston, this is Endeavor.
휴스턴, 여긴 엔디버다 그들을 발견했다
반복한다, 발견했다
We have'em in sight.
I repeat, we have'em in sight.
Master Bra'tac,...
브라탁 교관님
말로는 감사를 표현할 수 없군요
..words cannot express our gratitude.
당신이 텍사스의 하몬드군요
You are Hammond, of Texas?
I am.
그렇습니다
훌륭한 전사들이오
Your warriors serve you well.
I know they will be sorry
to see you return home so soon.
급히 돌아가신다니 서운하군요
돌아가야 합니다
I must return, before word
of our rebellion reaches Chulak.
우리의 반란 이야기가 출락에 전해지기 전에
내가 있어야 할 곳이오
My place is there.
This way, sir. We want to ask
a few questions before you leave.
이쪽입니다, 가시기 전에 몇 가지 여쭐 게 있습니다
Not bad at all.
괜찮은 날이었어...
SG1...누군가가 보고 싶다는군
SG-1, there's someone
who'd like to see you.
대니얼!
Daniel.
Space monkey.
우주 원숭이구만! 됐어!
Yeah!